Finding Aid for the Paul Bullock Papers LSC.1303
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul Bullock papers
1967-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bullock, Paul
LSC.1303
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Paul Bullock (1924-1986) was a research economist at the UCLA Institute of Industrial Relations (1953-85). The collection consists of audio tapes on reels and cassettes, transcripts, manuscript drafts, and clippings related to Bullock's research for three published books. The books are, Watts: The aftermath / by the people of Watts (1970), Youth in the labor market: employment patterns and career aspirations in Watts and East Los Angeles (1972), and Jerry Voorhis, the idealist as politician (1978).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Bullock, 1982.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997095153606533
Biography
Bullock was born in Pasadena, California, on November 6, 1924; received his BA and MA, Occidental College, 1948 and 1949; performed graduate work, UCLA, 1948-50; economics instructor, El Camino College (1949-50) and Occidental College (1950-51); research economist, UCLA Institute of Industrial Relations, 1953-85; published writings include: Watts: The aftermath / by the people of Watts (1969), Youth in the labor market: employment patterns and career aspirations in Watts and East Los Angeles (1972), Creative careers: minorities in the arts (1977), and Jerry Voorhis, the idealist as politician (1978); founder and president, Jazz Heritage Foundation; died February 14, 1986.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of audio tapes on reels and cassettes, transcripts, manuscript drafts, and clippings related to Bullock's research for three published books. The books are, Watts: The aftermath / by the people of Watts (1970), Youth in the labor market: employment patterns and career aspirations in Watts and East Los Angeles (1972), and Jerry Voorhis, the idealist as politician (1978).
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Audio tapes, transcripts, and drafts for Watts: the aftermath (Boxes 1-2).
Audio tapes and transcripts for Jerry Voorhis (Boxes 3-4).
Audiotapes.; Watts (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- Social conditions -- Research.; Economists -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- California -- Archives.; Bullock, Paul--Archives.; Voorhis, Jerry, 1901- .
- Audio Tapes
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This series contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Watts; the Aftermath. New York: Grove Press, 1969
    - Armstead and Townsend, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_001a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:53:37) (Box 1, Case 1)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
      Scope and Contents
      Transcribed from container: "Armstead-Townsend on magazine articles" Transcribed from insert: "Start #225 9/6/66"
    - Armstead and Townsend, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_001b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:21:04) (Box 1, Case 1)
    - Conversation with Gary Davis, Ernest Walker, Willie Willis, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_002; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:42:40) (Box 1, Case 2)
      Content note: Transcribed 1967 January 6
    - Two Discussions with Teenagers, 1967 January 2; yrlsc_1303_001_003; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:15:43) (Box 1, Case 3)
      Condition note: streaming file slowed down for audibility. Content note: Transcribed 1967 February 7
    - Negro leaders, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_004a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:52:05) (Box 1, Case 4)
      Content note: Transcribed 1967 November 28
    - Negro leaders, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_004b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:33:25) (Box 1, Case 4)
    - Police and Drugs, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_005a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:09:55) (Box 1, Case 5)
      Condition note: one voice recorded at 3 3/4:9.5 cm., and one at 15/16:2.4 cm. Content note: Transcribed 1967 November 28
    - Police and Drugs, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_005b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:44:39) (Box 1, Case 5)
    - Last tape (Drugs), undated; yrlsc_1303_001_006a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:46:58) (Box 1, Case 6)
      Cotent note: Transcribed 1967 December 16
    - Last tape (Drugs), undated; yrlsc_1303_001_006b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 3:40:49) (Box 1, Case 6)
    - Negro Revolution (with Jimmy Thomas mostly), Earnest Walker, Albert Graham, etc., undated; yrlsc_1303_001_007a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:30:56) (Box 1, Case 7)
    - Negro Revolution (with Jimmy Thomas mostly), Earnest Walker, Albert Graham, etc., undated; yrlsc_1303_001_007b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:02:24) (Box 1, Case 7)
    - Interviews by Jimmy Thomas, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_008a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:32:20) (Box 1, Case 8)
    - Interviews by Jimmy Thomas, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_008b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:25:10) (Box 1, Case 8)
    - Sedgie Collins, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_009a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:36:05) (Box 1, Case 9)
      Content note: Reel 1 of 2
    - Sedgie Collins, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_009b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:05) (Box 1, Case 9)
      Content note: Reel 2 of 2
  - "Watts Tape #2"
    Scope and Contents note
    Undated or post-dated tapes found in envelope marked "Watts Tape#2".
    These appear to have been used in preparing Aspiration vs. Opportunity; "Careers" in the Inner City (Ann Arbor: Institute of labor and Industrial Relations, University of Michigan--Wayne State University, 1973), and the trade edition of Youth in the Labor market: Employment Patterns and Career Aspirations in Watts and East Los Angeles [Los Angeles: Manpower Research Center, Institute of Industrial Relations, University of California, 1972].
    - East Los Angeles tape, 1971 June 22; yrlsc_1303_001_010; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:48:15) (Box 1, Case 10)
    - Watts Teens, 1971 June 23; yrlsc_1303_001_011; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:07:09) (Box 1, Case 11)
      Transcribed from reel: Watts Teenage School Counseling. June 23 by 13 Watts youngsters.
    - Confidential tape #1/School Counseling, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_012a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 2:36:13) (Box 1, Case 12)
      Transcribed from reel: Beginning- Confidential #1, End- School Counseling Doresey, Locke, Jordan.
    - Confidential tape #1/School Counseling, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_012b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:37:21) (Box 1, Case 12)
    - Watts tape 312, undated; yrlsc_1303_001_013; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:03:53) (Box 1, Case 13)
      Transcribed from insert: Watts tape 312- stop when you come to the part concerning teen past. Taoe recorder at the shop (ACF).
- Watts; the Aftermath. New York: Grove Press, 1969
  - Transcripts and Drafts of Unidentified Sections of the Book
    - Watts tape., (1 item, 41 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Paul, Bob, Willie, Earnest, Gary., (1 item, 42 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Paul Bullock, Richard Townsend, William Armstead., (1 item, 7 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Donnie [Bradley?]., (1 item, 8 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gregory., (1 item, 1 piece) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - James., (1 item, 4 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Paul Williams., (4 items, 101 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Some or all of this material may also pertain to Aspiration vs. Opportunity: "Careers" in the Inner City. Ann Arbor: Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, University of Michigan--Wayne State University, 1973.
      i) Number Two tape [Education] 1 item, 10 pieces.
      ii) Tape #3. 1 item, 20 pieces.
      iii) Paul Williams. 1 item, 69 pieces.
      iv) On police, concluding remarks. 1 item, 2 pieces.
    - Sedgie Collins., (2 items, 24 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      i) March 1969. 1 item, 7 pieces.
      ii)"My name is Sydney Sedgie Collins..." 1 item, 17 pieces.
    - [Job seeking. Tommy]., (1 item, 4 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - [Job programs. Frank. Westminster program]., (1 item, 30 pieces - p.7 wanting) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "One thing whites must realize..." and "The majority of middle class people...", (2 items, 6 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Drafts of Identified Sections of Watts; the Aftermath. New York: Grove Press, 1969
    - "The Authors: (p. [v] of the book)., (1 item, 1 piece) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Paul Williams., (2 item, 24 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 13)
      i) "Paul Williams (April 1969)" (pp.77-89 of the book).
      ii) #1 Tape: "the Middle Class" (pp. 182-183 of the book). 2 items, 6 pieces.
    - "The Contributors" (pp.278-284 of the book)., (6 items, 12 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 14)
      i) "The Contributors". 1 item, 6 pieces.
      ii) Robert Mason. 3 items, 3 pieces.
      iii) Richard Townsend. 1 item, 1 piece.
      iv) Paul Williams. 1 item, 2 pieces.
  - Interviews of Jerry Voorhis by Paul Bullock
    - Interview, February 11, 1971; Tape no.1; (3 items, 104 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Interview., [February 11, 1971]; Tape no.2; (3 items, 90 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Interview., March 12, 1971; Tape no.3; (2 items, 56 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Interview., [April 1, 1971]; Tape no.4; (1 item, 22 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Interview., April 29, 1971; Tape no.5; (3 items, 66 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Interview., [May 20, 1971]; Tape no.6; (1 item, 34 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Interview., June 11, 1971; Tape no.7; (1 item, 26 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Interview., [July 7, 1971]; Tape no.8; (1 item, 22 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Interview., [July 13, 1971]; Tape no.9; (1 item, 23 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Interview., August 11, 1971; Tape no.10; (1 item, 27 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Final tape. Interview., October 12, 1971; Tape no.11; (3 items, 61 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Interview., July 3, 1972; Tape no.12; (1 item, 6 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Interview., June 22, 1973; Tape no.13; (1 item, 15 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 13)
- The Congressional Election Campaign of 1946
  - Newspaper Transcripts Concerning Jerry Voorhis's 1946 Congressional Election Campaign Against Richard Nixon
    - Alhambra Post Advocate., January 1, 1945-November 5, 1946; (2 items, 89 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      i) Transcript (photocopy). 1 item, 85 pieces.
      ii) Manuscript. 1 item, 4 pieces.
    - Covina Argus-Citizen., August 3, 1945-November 8, 1946; (1 item, 18 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - El Monte Herald., April 13, 1945-November 1, 1946; (1 item, 31 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Monrovia Daily News Post., August 16, 1945-October 31, 1946; (1 item, 19 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Pomona Progress Bulletin., Time period July 3, 1945-November 4, 1946; (1 item, 143 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - South Pasadena Review., April 27, 1945-April 20, 1946; (1 item, 39 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - South Pasadena Review., April 19-November 28, 1946; (1 item, 21 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Whittier News., April 14, 1945-November 8, 1946; (1 item, 128 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Interviews Concerning the 1946 Congressional Election
    - Earl C. Adams. Interview., November 12, 1971; (2 items, 47 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Leisa Bronson. Interview., November 19, 1971; (1 item, 16 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - George Brown. Interview., August 6, 1971; (1 item, 16 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Roy Crocker. Interview., March 7, 1972; (2 items, 26 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Roy O.Day. Interviews., June 23, 1972 and November 19, 1971; (7 items [including duplicates], 74 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 13)
      i) Addendum to 1971.
      ii) Photocopy of A.L.S. to R.O.D. 1946.
      iii) Photocopy of newspaper clipping.
      iv) T.L.S. (with 3 copies).
    - John Anson Ford. Interview., June 24, 1971; (1 item, 15 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Paul Heiser. Interview., March 21, 1972; (1 item, 14 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Stanley Long. Interview., August 24, 1971; (1 item, 32 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Harrison McCall. Interview., October 21, 1971; (3 items, 83 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Zita Remley. Interview., July 15, 1971; (2 items, 52 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Richard Richards. Interview., n.d.; (1 item, 12 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Zetterberg. Interview., August 6, 1971; (1 item, 29 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Jerry Voorhis Material
    - Questions on the 1946 Voorhis-Nixon Congressional campaign., (1 item, 1 piece) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Voorhis biography., (2 items, 2 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 22)
      [Notes on the Japnese internment from Richard R. Lingeman, Don't You Know There's A War On? New York: Putnam, 1970.]